Claudio Villanueva

Mobile Engineer

OBJECTIVE

Create software of the best quality considering all its aspects, such as user experience, maintainability, scalability and testability.

EXPERIENCE

iOS Engineer at Unicomer [Costa Rica, remote]

Jan 2023 - Now

Money loan iOS app development. Junior devs mentoring. Establish best programing practices and architecture decisions making. CI/CD pipelines configuration and troubleshooting. Certificate pinning implementation. Regular and UI tests writing. App internal mock services implementation for testing purposes.

iOS Engineer at Leafly [USA, remote]

Jan 2022 - Jan 2023

Leafly customer iOS app development. Migration functionality from UIKit/rxSwift to SwiftUI/Combine. Implementation of new features. Bitrise CI/CD pipelines configuration. Tests writing using Quick/Nimble, Snapshot.

iOS Engineer at Transbank [Chile, in person]

Aug 2020 - Dec 2021

Transbank Customers iOS app & iOS Digital Wallet development. Regular and UI tests writing. Mobile apps security assessments. Static analysis tools. PCI-DSS standard fullfilment.

iOS Engineer at WOM [Chile, in person]

Mar 2019 - Jul 2020

WOM Customers iOS app. Junior devs mentoring. Lead developer. Architectural decisions making. New features and improvements. Security checks following OWASP.

CONTACT

claudioff@gmail.com +56 9 2776 1464 https://cvillanueva.github.io Santiago, Chile

ABOUT ME

I am passionate about software development, with 12 years of experience creating software and 8 years focused in mobile apps. Beyond considering myself as a mobile specialist I really enjoy participating in all sort of projects using different tech stacks.

EDUCATION

University of Santiago, 2007 Bachelor in Computer Science & Engineering.

TOOLS

IOS Development, Swift, SwiftUI, Combine, UIKit, rxSwift, Objective-C, Fastlane, Alamofire, URLSession, GraphQL, Firebase.

Android Development, Java, Kotlin, Jetpack, Coroutines, Retrofit.

Network tools, like Proxyman, Charles Proxy, Postman, Insomnia.

EXPERIENCE

Mobile Engineer at Garapon TV [Japan, in person]

Apr 2017 - Mar 2019

Garapon iOS & Android HLS streaming apps development. Backend development using Golang. Server side HLS Streaming development. Integration of VLC library into Android apps. R&D about computer vision. AWS resources management.

Software Engineer at Pixtoome [Chile, in person]

Apr 2013 - Mar 2017

iOS & Android apps development. API design and Backend development using Scala language. SQL Databases modeling, programing and administration. AWS resources management.

Software Engineer at Ubix [Chile, in person]

Dec 2009 - Mar 2013

iOS & Android apps development. API design and Backend development using Java language. SQL Databases modeling, programing and administration. ZeroMQ based apps development.

Software Engineer at Nuwit [Chile, in person]

Oct 2007 - Nov 2009

Blackberry apps development. Java EE web apps development. Weblogic, Glassfish and Tomcat deployment.

REFERENCES

Grant Stevens

(Former) Software Engineering Manager at Leafly. grant@grantstevens.me

SKILLS

Great knowledge of mobile apps architecture and a variety of programming patterns.

Code reviews. Pair programing. Junior devs mentoring.

Mobile apps securitization, Certificate pinning, MTLS, Good security practices.

Backend development with Golang and Elixir languages.

Linux OS administration, scripting.

Database modeling. SQL.

Cloud resources administration, AWS, Azure and Digital Ocean.

Video streaming based apps development iOS, Android and server side.

Great knowledge of Agile-Scrum methodology.